Ok, here...
Good-morning or I just I guess right at noon.
Welcome to the first ...session of
build twenty fifteen my name's kevin miller I'm a program manager on
...hyper scale computing team...as your and going-to-take you on a little bit of a
tour of building iterative things solutions on as are both
with technologies that are available today and a little bit of hence of things
to come mostly I'm going to demos things that are that already exist.
And, I just have to remember which...part here okay so evaluations
...is great time.
So, let me sort of set this up and give a
couple of ground rules one is that internet of things.
Is the most hyped thing
...your guide...a...for how many times I say the word thing during this talk okay
good so it's the most hypes thing I've worked on a long-time in the industry and I was
here for the original browser wars I have been through a lot of like my god this is going to change everything
moments and this one this one's a do the but, there is
...there but there is also this problem where, you know,
weird stuff is happening old things are getting new names batches now
called...path analytics...cool again if anybody knows a
little excel may have data scientist on their business card now there's just,
you know, there's crazy talk I had a vendor visit me
...two weeks ago and he told me that his solution had infinite scale
and perfect security and he did not laugh after he said that right so,
there are there are some special people out there right now?
But, like I said there is there is
...to try to talk a little bit about...path of righteousness if you will
and this crazy world because you can make a big difference if you
think about things a little differently than you did before and if you saddle up.
Anybody who tells you that like security is perfect and easy
and I ot is...and
...security is not something you can give to somebody else security
is everybody's problem...if you...the cloud providers problem it's your problem
it is everybody you hires problem is everybody who works for use problem and.
We have learn this the hard way...big scar my hand from the security words
...microsoft so, you know, you got a satellite.
I'm going to talk.
Patterns and...patterns a little bit things that
I've observed from my own experiments and from talking to a lot of customers and partners I'm going to spend.
Probably a third of the time...so doing a demo.
Talk a little bit about how you can get...to the future from here.
So, I can hinted at this before but really the first question
that when somebody talks about it I tend to hear one of to answers,
you know, one of these is like...I've been doing
...is before you were born and I am not like twenty either right and there's some truth to that
command and control has a lot to do with I ot there's a lot of overlap there
and people have been doing command control for fifty years and then the so, you know,
there's some truth to that view and then there's the other view which is
You know, it's going to change everything and there's a little truth to that one too I
...to sound guy was really loud and he's really glad I warn them so,
like I said the truth is...between both of these things do.
Have some truce to them because?
With the continuation of moore's law with
ubiquitous pretty close to ubiquitous connectivity and really low-price
on communications you really can do...you couldn't do before kind of a way that I
think about this myself and I think about where the industry is today is that.
There's sort of two extreme swear...is pretty mature and works fine
now one extreme is where the thing is super
complicated super-expensive or the cost of that thing failure
is completely unacceptable and you can't even go there to think about what would
cost betting failed so in that case.
You know, you can load some expense into the system you can build
a one of software solution and it's okay you can put a lot of expensive sensors
...expensive communication devices in place and it's okay and that's really kind of where the
command and control world came from.
And, the other extreme is where the thing is really sample.
canonical examples thermostat so it can really only do three things.
That can tell you what temperature is...can tell you what the temperature supposed to be
an you can set the temperature so
really the analysis for this is not what you call super complex.
If you have thermostat and refrigerators and
...thousand of them and nine hundred ninety eight of them say it's thirty four degrees and everyone
...seventy two it's
...does not taken analytical engine to figure out which.
Refrigerator might be broken so you can do those simple scenarios
because for one the analysis is not...hard and
secondly if you have a lot of them you can advertiser software cost over a lot
of units so therefore you can keep the cost down and I would argue that.
The middle.
Is the challenge variety like if it's real simple find...now if it's
a rocket define do it now if you want to do something in the middle it's
really hard now and I think the challenge for the industry and really this is kind of the historic microsoft
playbook as we want move towards the middle from both of those extremes want to make it easier for some smart
person who's trying to figure this out...garage to do more easily at the same time we want to make it
so that the complex solution is not crazy complex and...affordable if you're
not talking about millions of multi-million-dollar devices?
So, the kind of building blocks of this.
Are really the services that, you know, the as your services...
Really at some level I don't care who's software you're running as long as it,
you know, interacts with my software but you have these.
Sort of segments you're looking at how do I think about the data on the device how do I think about connecting the
device.
To the cloud.
How do I store data that I care about how do I do analysis either,
you know, patchy analysis...plenty of time and...to figure out how to design next the next generation
...I want to look at see how the current when did for more real-time thing
...to fire sprinklers on if there's a fire?
But, you have...sorties hot path and...path analytics activities
and you want to do something with that data you want to create a worker you want to visualize the data you want to
send alerts you want to send messages there's a lot
of there's a lot going on there and.
One of the things that we announced convergence last month was this rotc
sweet and really the goal of that is to try to make
it much easier to deploy manage operate
...solutions that span a bunch of different it services.
So, this kind of brings me to my first, you know,
pattern slash...pattern for the talk which is.
Based on...of it solutions that I've seen good ones and bad ones it's really
...think big from the beginning but start small.
Pretty much everything that you.
Do you want to go to learn from you want to see it evolve you're going to find
in the course of building these solutions that what you thought was the cases probably not the case?
You're going to take these steps through you're going to go...that's not the data that was actually helpful
...have the wrong sensor...a bunch of data and all I'm doing with it
...it forever and,... we
appreciate the money but really that's not your what your business should be doing so,
if you think about these things.
Prototyping is your friend...proofs of concept
...your friend his way easier to adjust which she will almost certainly
have to.
If you start small now while starting small it's really important to think about the fact
you do want to get big and.
It's a lot and you don't want to as you go from prototype to have a life events right you don't want to go
...work great a hundred now want to do million.
So, I have to throw out everything that I thought about...so you have to kind of balance these
two slightly conflicting priorities where you're saying okay I'm going to a prototype I'm going
to do a few devices I'm going to try to figure out what
...I really need before deployed I'm...try to figure out how to manage them how to manage
identity how to manage the device how to update the device how to secure the device
think about all that stuff early when it's easy to
...come back from a mistake and it's cheap much cheaper of course the
...pattern here is let's ship a whole bunch of them and then figure out how the
manage them or how to deploy them how to secure...we've had some
really unhappy customers have gone out and you come to visit us and say hey we built this thing and we
deployed a million things and then how do we have...firmware on I'm like?
Well, the first thing you have to do is build a time machine.
And, go back to before you start them all out there.
And, think about management.
And, you know, really.
That's not what the customer wants to hear right but that
is sort of the way reality works here and so.
Think about security management think about scale like if,
you know, eventually going to have a lot of data you want something that can really ingest a lot of data
there's a lot of work with event hubs today which is really pretty compelling because the amount of data
that those things can snort up I think is the technical phrase is pretty amazing?
So, in this context of thinking about the architecture for the solution thinking both big and
small.
...take a little detour and talk about the thing itself.
One of the challenges that
the industry faces really is that the.
That things are so heterogeneous temperature
...is an incredibly simple thing.
But, pretty quickly the things get complicated and powerful even I mean I have a little beagle
...thing that I'm using a part of my demo and it's kind of
astonishing how powerful that little dude is cheap.
There's lots of smaller...bigger and once you get to large
things then you start getting into logical collections
...things that you want to manage as a single
entity sometimes so ...a truck on
the highway is a complex thing buttruck in the context of a fleet management solution.
Requires you to think about these.
Objects very differently you know,
the far-right there the graphic is intended to suggest a smart city which is
obviously an extremely heterogeneous collection of stuff.
And, some of that stuff gets buried...concrete for fifty years so how you
think about again management and deployments and security
updates frankly warranty periods.
...like it's just different so ...as we've been developing the architecture
...what we're doing.
We have to think about extreme hardware and software.
Heterogeneity right so.
...operating systems things that don't really have an operating system very complicated collections of
objects conference room is an object corporate campuses an object
...building as an object city.
So, the architectural requirements
...that drive for us or things like okay we have to make sure that we scale.
And, we are secure by default and we.
Can provide latency guarantees one is required?
I'm going to talk about security some more on that I want to talk about
defense in-depth here but I'll talk about little bit more and then there's a point you to talk clemens back in this room
a couple of hours is going to go far deeper and security and all.
The time that
we're doing that stuff we have to do what I was sort of hinting at earlier is that
we've make it much easier to get going to go from zero to I have a
...you know, ...have a prototype of a proof of concept and then I can go...
relatively smoothly from proof of concept to final release without having a life events?
So, the second sort of
...want to talk about here a little bit is telemetry first and.
This is a really important I think because most of if
not all of the successful...solutions I've seen
...started with telemetry and then moved from telemetry to command control and.
There's a couple of good reasons for doing telemetry first one is that you're just you just
don't know really unless you're really, really the wizard
if you are we have jobs but if you unless you're really,
really the wizard you're going to find stuff that you did not expect
...the course of doing this like one of the promises...
the machine learning...something it actually delivers is that the machine learning pines patterns
that the people didn't see so if you don't do telemetry first.
And, get the data...it and see what you have it's really hard to know what you need
what you can do what your options are so telemetry first is a big deal
the other reason telemetry...first is it's a lot nicer to do.
Security and privacy work under telemetry
scenarios that is to find out those the hard way when you doing command control so
if I'm connected vehicle and I there's a hack
in the thing but it's telemetry only then okay,
yeah, somebody could find out my gps location I don't love that idea.
I actually don't care but as a public figure would
really care maybe you could infer some information about the vehicle and get
...ip advantage of your competitor from that but really
the grand scheme of things that's not all that scary by comparison to command control
with somebody in the vehicle...you turn it off once on the freeway.
So,you know, a factory automation similar
...worst-case scenario if I have a telemetry breach well maybe somebody can figure out how many do
dads my robots but last month and that's bad but I can
take an action back on the device and actually cause it to fail.
A lot worse.
So, again, it's a lot easier to work your way through security and privacy
implications for what you're doing if you do it based on telemetry and the other thing that I think I
would add about telemetry in general is that.
You also have to think about the data not just the data that you're trying to measure with the device but the data
of the device how do you think about device telemetry that's telling you something about the
environment the devices in verses telemetry the tells you how the devices
doing.
... my...my in troubled do I need do I need help so the
...pattern is another one that I think is really important.
So, if I move on and think a little bit about telemetry specifically
...my laptop and understates and try use in a second.
The democrats and I...are collaborating well so far today and I want to
screw that up all right so the telemetry scenario than is kind of going back to that
thing big but start small think about telemetry furs a
good telemetry pattern we see a lot is use event hubs for data in
grass.
Because that via...ability also phrase are used
...smart...data really high scale easy easily configure
able then go into something extra
...you could use storm for my demo today I'm using stream analytics.
And, then you
stream analytics to do some analysis on-the-fly in real-time and also split the data off so
that it goes somewhere else for longer-term storage or later analysis with something
like nl and this is a pretty common telemetry pattern that we've seen a lot of times
want to do some data in...to do a little bit of real-time ish processing on it make some decisions and,
quickly and then I want to put the data somewhere cheap.
So, that I can come back to it later and do machine learning on it?
So, these two components and there's a lot there's a lot of content
is conference about these two components I'm going to kinda go over the slightly here so,
for events...really.
You just have to think about.
How quickly the pipe can get your data from point a to point b?
Have to provide security configure ability
high volume low latency data transfer and sense
of an have support in...p and http there's a lot of publishers that you
sort of get free on the way n and the scale
here is pretty astonishing now it's at this point we're measuring data
in trillions of messages not millions or billions so the you know,
that's a really powerful thing and then moving from their industry mavericks
for processing the data and...come back a little bit fast
path connections after the demo but really?
...about two systems that are designed for extremely high data throughput
so you have the ability to quickly get input and analysis of the
data and...stream analytics you get this extension that you can use a sequel like
languages really sequel plus a couple of three commands but allows you to do it
makes some time-based decisions and
it really provides a lot of our so,
then for my demo I decided that I would do the demo...ifwas some random dude
somewhere my boss said hey check out this stuff so?
I wrote a little website that generates sample
according to probability distribution send that to event hubs from event...a
...analytics extremely excess split the stream push everything the blob for
later looking around and then
I have an action path which I've done with sequel here just because it's easy to
...demo easy to look at along the way but really if I was building the solution the
...messaging system that I would go to and then because I'm going to sequel I have a worker role here
that snowed that's going to take the data from
sequel and send it back to my website so I can display.
Okay, all right so have a little website here.
Unless you pick a probability distribution a number of seconds to run.
And, mean value something to do the kind of this backwards chai squared
distribution and I run it so I go off and I generate a bunch of
data and I have a little monte carlo simulation there that's making sure that the data can
forms to a patterns so this is just, you know, I've got some data maybe it's pressure data
...on really care for the purposes of this and the pattern that
...in the field is...a...low values and that's fine and sy you
know, build-up to some relatively sothe...here's...about a hundred
...a relatively csharp tail off on the right side so you have the data and
...the data is within this sort of normal distribution is what you expect.
Okay, so, I.
Kind of.
Flipped back here really quickly.
So, in my javascript basically create a little json
package.
The reading which is a floating-point number and device id.
And, that's all that's all that I do there.
So, in my website have the little thing that checks to see if something fits under the curve of.
Of this transcribe distribution which I can tell you I had not done for a long long-time.
And, then I want to send the data to the client and
...in the interest of airing dirty laundry.
At this point I do not have a javascript sdk for event hubs
...one we'll let you do this in any language uone but at
for the purposes of this demo I used when it was written by one...in vp guy named
...who...a little javascript?
Sdk may be real happy when I found it
also gave me something to give people matching grief about not having which was a double.
So, this what all this all this
...javascript extension let you do is you can create.
A clients.
And, ...event happenstance then.
Create a message and send a message let me switch.
Back here so I go to the management consul.
And, have a service...name space?
Of creative this event...the packet already but creating event have
is turns out super easy if you have a service best name
space you just go create event and, I did the quick create for this demo
...had to do is specify and name for the event hub in a region.
And, the...name space obviously so I create that then.
Inside the event.
I can configure it and again I just took the defaults have a one-day retention and
here was important part from my demo I created a shared access policy that would allow me to send
data to it so I have a send telemetry.
Sas and key.
So, then when I went into my javascript?
It's just easier to see here that ...ascii snippet.
That was ...was central imagery from the.
Site and then this ascii there sets a time-out then all
I do for to...send the data is the message.
New event data just json a pfizer and
then send message...and lets me handle any errors so just a few
lines of javascript and data is flowing back up.
To the event...so now I need.
Which I really...started...okay so?
So, my stream analytics job than similarly to create one of these.
In data services stream analytics quick create.
Give a job name a region and I have to have a storage account
in that region for monitoring but again the quick create...the stream
analytics job then I had to create and input and output
...that data to go to so the input is the event hub and this was one of the nicest experiences I had
...whole thing where I just said point...the event of test connection...said okay
...all done then output in this particular case the
first one I'm doing is that outputs to blob storage and so.
I created a friendly name for the blob storage
...storage account gave it the key.
And, container inside that lob storage.
So, now the only thing left to do is to create the query.
So, I could of use just said select star route from event have
the blob storage and be done and just, you know, like twenty-five characters which shows you how quickly
you can actually get legitimate things going on here but I wanted to show
expanded the star here because I wanted to show that in addition to those to data fields
that came in from my javascript event...as tagged the data as a
...has it has gone through with an event processing time.
So, I have the device id.
The reading and now this additional field event process to utc time.
So, now this goes.
Out to my...and the...out here are
just the friendly names that I created when I configured my inputs and outputs.
So, now if I go back here.
And, run this thing again.
Then data will start flowing...the as your storage explore.
Give it a second here...not...far good another refresh.
Make sure and look at the most recent one ...
So, now my data is flowing through and I see that.
...that I have the series of device id reading and date
time so now so that now my paths to where I can start doing
machine learning on this data is complete and I've written.
A few lines of javascript and one...life-like query.
...a little more.
Shows a little bit more the our of stream analytics here.
National emait show you...here so it's easier to see.
So, now I have.
A query where I say ok based on my personal
observations working with these things or based on machine learning I at now that's
the found a pattern that I want to taken action on and relatively real-time right so I
go okay in this probability distribution I was talking about let's see that's a pressure gate and I know
that the pressure goes up over a hundred fifteen
twice within a fifteen second period and I probably ought to think about doing something ...
this is just made...example but I think it is a pretty,
pretty reflective of a lot of real-world scenarios that we've been talking about
with our customers and partners so the differences here from sort of standard
sequel are really...a couple things one is you see in the
from the field that I'm specifying which field I want to use
as the critical time in my calculations and then at the top the select statement is just, you know,
I'm...time stamp these so later when
I'm looking back at them I can go okay that was when I found this anomaly.
Taking the device id and the count...account refers to.
The number of times that I find.
This value over a hundred fifteen in a sliding window
...seconds and that sliding window is clearly one of the other major
additions from streaming analytics and it's really.
Kind of astonishing because I was trying to think how I would do this without
something like this and also solutions involved me writing a lot of coding swearing and a lot of
old ancient languages I don't even know right because this is just not
trivial to do in like regular sequel and a programming language.
So, there's three different types of these sliding windows there's one sliding window which says, you know, I
want non overlapping windows of a certain length.
There's another one that says I want overlapping ones.
And, then the...the what is the most.
...screen version of that which is a continually sliding window where the windows slides on
every incoming event so you can actually see anything that happens in any arbitrary sliding fifteen
second window and the work that the team did to make that possible is pretty cool.
...then just for completion so you can see how the rest of the demo works
...another select statement in here to have to select statements
in one job which.
Probably makes sense sometimes it doesn't make sense other times and the stream
...probability...talking a lot more about that and talks that they have coming up but
...this particular case I just also blasting all the data into a different sequel table.
So, I can see so, later on I could do a query that says okay if I get
...alert about this device now want to go back and call out the
sequel and get all the data that devices...and over
...this recent time period so if I go to.
...these two.
Tables alerts.
Which is just all the data
...counts which is the number of times that I
find the bad and reading during that time period so let me?
Okay, not clean.
All right so now if I go back and run the sucker again.
I should see the to stream analytics jobs running one that's just pushing everything the blob
...later the other one that's doing the analysis
...finding me the misbehaving devices so I can do something with them.
So, now if I go back and refresh that query.
Then I see that have this incoming stream of devices hennessy that device ninety-four and
sixty-two...sixty nine each had
two bad readings within a fifteen second window.
So, now how that's required for me to do to sort of complete the
loop back on my demo is to reach is to connect
than that sql data back to the website so I can reported here.
So, if I go.
Now I have.
A call from
my website that just goes get stream lx results just as a post.
Sends with it a start date time so I can
Which results I want to look at?
And, then in my node job.
I have that post define I use the...
node extension so I can create a...request connection and request and
then just to my query which basically says someone anything that's on this date time.
Later than that time that I've been passed n.
groups note or...is so now I started the node job.
Snagajob can run this again.
And, unless the demo...get me on random numbers right now.
After a few seconds I'll start seeing.
The data comes in and I'll start seeing a table here at the bottom
that has machines that have been identified as being outside.
That range.
Hey, I paid my demo guide...this month jar right so,
now so now sort of completed that loop
and the thing that I think is important here.
Is...back here?
That was really not very much code.
You know, those...of javascript to get the thing inI did you now get in
little, you know, I used to be a developer mode and screw around the website a lot of money
...simulation stuff like that really the functional parts of this code
were, you know, a few...javascript push data up.
A...lines of an extended sequel syntax.
To run time-based queries and then a little a worker role
that basically completed the loop so if you were doing this interview on a
real deployment we messaging at the back-end but that that's sort of model holds up
and we see this one over and over and over with customers that are doing it for the first-time,
you know, the first step is like they get some telemetry and I want to take some action based on the telemetry,...
they have some machine that occasionally does something and...does something,
something needs to happen.
You know, it's a it's a machine it's something that you know.
Collects.
Samples and its full and...we picked up you know, it's.
I need...industrial-strength mold killer my backyard and if they had
one then when you know, the...killer would call the guy...it before my dogged
...a lot-a lot of scenarios some silly but?
A ton of scenarios go back to the same pattern when I see some data I
want to take some action if anybody you're staying at the marriott marquis.
View...elevators one elevator...out in...tower
...in this morning and dude...fixing elevator...a lot of noise
but fixing elevator which is great maybe with some telemetry he could have been fix
...two o'clock in the morning instead
of at about eight thirty this morning when everybody was trying to get out of it
...that hotel and come here.
And, again, it's a simple scenario get some telemetry...that needs to happen in your
...truck in this particular case because some due to complexity elevator but.
Probably they didn't know until some by the notice that the...and called them.
So, this is...these scenarios are really kind of everywhere easy to get started
...kind of follows that pattern I was talking about earlier about do telemetry first
start small start with personalize devices is one of the things that we're shipping is
the ability to create a lot of virtual devices and hit systems that scale.
So, this briefly to another pattern that are almost learn the hard way building
us demo which is don't stick your head in the fire hose unless...doing.
And, that's b because it's tempting to go you know,
what I need to like massages data?
Someone put a little worker in here to massage of data well don't do that between
to high-bandwidth components unless you really know what you're...
Event...can push a humongous amount of data
...can input a humongous amount of data is
way smarter in general unless you're really, you know, the wizard on this stuff.
To do if you have to do any processing assessing that data do it before it
gets in the fat pipe or after comes out of the fat pipe not in the middle I mean I
...polite version of this and...said don't stick your head and fire hose and I thought
okay that's more memorable high-ranking on have to...that one.
...really do hates to...given anything.
So, let me look here and make sure that on sort of kind of on the right path ok.
So, then the force pattern then is about defense in-depth and like I said before
...as a talking here to o'clock resent talk a lot more about security than I am but?
You can't.
Put security in after the fact you really have really have to be a cultural thing and you
can't go all the cloud vendors in charge of security because that's not going to work either
if you're going to get into this business you have to be willing to think about your business
differently you have to think about things that maybe you really never had to think about before.
Because now you might by paying something on the internet become an interesting
...target when you haven't been before like there's been a lot of stuff in the news recently about connected
car hacks and connect car possible hacks what five years ago if you want to hackett car
...the physical access to the car and you might get
beat up and if you succeeded in hacking you got one.
Which is not really very interesting target I'm
resisting like physical security they had one car not really very actually if I could say
thousands of miles away and potentially...a lot of them okay that's interesting I mean, you know,
...not to me I hope ...being recorded I want to get too much trouble?
And, the other thing that comes up in thinking about defense in-depth
is you have to think early and often about it so you know,
one of my favorite examples...if you have.
A thing and it's got an app so now my thing is controllable my
phone okay that's great what sell the thing.
You know, contributes a big thing like a car and I had like an
unlocking start the car
...my phone and it is a nice secure connection to that car and now I sell the car.
And, now, you know, I walk by it and started up.
It's almost a trivial thing.
Because you really wouldn't think about it necessarily in the course of building
car but that was a scenario or building the thing whatever you're connected
thing is right so this is kinda highlights the
fact that you have to just have to think about this throughout the entire process and,
the people like us who have been doing stuff out in the open on the internet for a long-time of all learn
this the hard way that security has to be a,
... a lifelong practice and you have to think about it from
the very beginning you have to think about.
How do I think about the commandments like
how does the thing think about the command here's an example...completely outside the io t
like banking I am not willing to have a lot of hurls between checking my balance I don't want like
seven factor authentication to check my balance because that would just irritate me to death?
But, you know, if my bank actually sent me a message to my phone and said
did you just try to wire ten thousand-dollars to, you know,
ammonium right I'm willing to type in the six digits to say yes or not or
no.
And, the...think about security of things in the same way like suddenly
of the thing is getting commands like it's never gotten before should it call
home and go hey mom is still you because you've never asked me to like semis of on fire before
...and that has to go in at the design level...I don't
want my connected robot surgeon to say
it's okay to do a firmware update well it's got my spleen and its technicals right I
wanted to have a local state machine that says, you know, I'm not listening now.
And, you have to think about that when you're designing
the thing not after you've deployed a bunch of them and it's got my spleen it's an okay.
...sure I mostly preaching acquire on this one by
...more moment because the security guys going to kill me by them you also have to think about.
The stack from the physical security the device all the way up to the application-level
to the policies that you put around data transport
it's a big deal so now
...talk a little bit about where we're going now from here so everything that
I built to this point and everything that I talked about this point is really stuff
that exist today, you know, go out go,
you know, go and do it we have customers who are deploying all this stuff we have where, you know,
infinitely more complicated scenarios in the little thing that I walk you through in real deployment based
on our architecture and that's great?
announces convergence last month there's a recorded talk.
By...dimaggio on the io t hub which is part of this
that's definitely worth a look.
But, the way we're trying to think about this and it kinda goes back to that picture
...at the very beginning of the bell curve is that we have to make
it much easier to do solutions in the middle solutions of things that
are more complicated than toys.
And, things that aren't so expensive the it's okay to spend hundreds of thousands of dollars
and software and monitoring per device.
Ninety some percent of the world is in between those two things I think so the
...really is our effort to make these things.
A lot easier to make it much quicker to
go from nothing to a working
deployments and then easily move from there to
...real proof of concept spiel deployments and production and
to do that in a much more predictable and understandable
fashion is currently the case...can see even in the case of the little demo that I did that I kind of
pick and choose some blocks from that original as your it services
charge and put them together so what we want to do is say okay,
you know, you're going to pick a scenario and we're going to instantiate an instance of a complete solution
basin that scenario and then you can go customize...to your heart's content,
you know, we might by default bitstream analytics and you might
...replace that with html site great we might, you know,
pick a storage and you...storage system and you would prefer to do another
one but the idea is that will very quickly and easily get you going
with real scenarios and the first three are the ones on the slide, you know,
remote monitoring asset management and predictive maintenance but.
Like I said a lot of these scenarios really similar once you get the
most alamos...ui piece peeled away and we're also using the
...to simplify the ...you think about how much do things cost.
Because it's for those of you built complicated solutions measure now month-to-month
building is kind of a miss a mysterious act there's a lot of takers running
and I may have to expense...bill this month for the first-time because I ran a lot of stuff and I
have no idea how much...cost me ...right...my checking account so hopefully I didn't go
crazily that thing running for like seven days around but,
we want to make the ability to budget for it much more predictable across
across as your and then going back to that start small but think big
...make sure that everything that we that we provide
in the solution has really high scale not infinite scaling perfect
security like the crazy guy offered me a couple weeks ago but that we want sure
we're staying ahead of anybody'srequirements to push the technologies part of the way
we're doing this is we kind of think about reference architecture for how you build
...things solutions on as your and starts with getting device
information and transports.
A gateway that manages inbound activity or in the case
of the ip sweet also command control and then within that gives you the ability
to use all of the our is provided by asher and
then also allow you to think...rationally
about the way you present data at the end so.
You know, the thing that I built fits in this architecture I used event hubs for the
cloud gateway I use stream analytics for the
event data processor I had a couple of different kinds of storage their
the control system worker role was my little node dot js job.
And, then in my particular case I was not
sending a command control back but, you know, that's a relatively straightforward thing to do with
...this architectures well and
that kind of brings me to my final pattern anti pattern which is if you think about that reference
...going to be publishing a lot more detail...the reference architecture but if you think about that record
reference architecture and build to it then.
Basically your experience becomes as more functionality shows up in the...
So, you can do stuff now but there's going-to be there in some cases there is going to be more work to do
...if you do try to command control.
And, use event hubs that's really
...method you have to figure out how to do
the commanding and you can do that and we have customer doing a today with
cues and topics and things like that this and information out but one of the things that comes
in the reference architect...part of the...
in ip hub which basically extends the capabilities of event
hubs to also allow device identity
device management security and command control so
the scenario becomes okay now I just have to send rather than having a, you know,
a q r topic worsening...the messaging system that's routing things back out to
my device now I can send a message back to the gateway
and the gateway will then do thatdo that forming and the other big peace that has not released yet
with was coming out very soon dan down here would probably say it's coming out this is kevin says
it's okay because...the...blocking right now is these
libraries for devices and this is a very portable
see ninety-nine library that runs on just about anything we have...running
...nothing's a small is thermostat and allows you
to quickly describe to the
gateway the capabilities of your device so you basically say here's stuff I know-how to do
...navigate way knows what sorts of data you can provide what sort of
actions you can take...based going
...other direction so really those are two big pieces of this and if you
...but toward the reference architecture
then you just sort of...the
...functionality more or less for free once those pieces come online?
I think I'm going to press my like just a little bit into a second demo.
Assuming academic password ok so this isthe event.
This maybe where the demo...getting.
...okay so this is one example of the event have
...of the client library this is the event of version
...quite simple because it's really not doing anything fancy with the data on...and,
what allows you to do then it's like I said this is
see ninety-nine so I have a running on a beagle bound up here?
And, you say okay I have a connection string which is the same
...string that I used to in my javascript...data and, event...paths with...
The library let me quickly create a data handle.
...that particular case I'm sticking so that same content in here that I was
using any other demo it's ...or reading and injure that's the.
Device id and then...error handling there because it's
c and then Icreate...client handle.
I should probably actually had...so you can see full-screen area.
And, then I send a message and there's a sense single which is what I use here or
there's a send batch where you can send an array of items.
And, then...see...clean-up after myself.
At the bottom.
If I go back here.
Really one more time.
Have a beagle down here?
Have that so...generating device ideas and readings
push them up so if I run this thing again?
This is definitely reading high which.
Unless...stopped my stream area and I had the beagle bun pick a device
idea over five hundred because I did I knew I didn't have any my virtual devices
...just...quickly pop up on the screen.
And, so.
So, adding the client that path was pretty much trivial.
And, then the other piece of...some gun I'm going to skip on
...atomic a couple questions is.
You can then use our by to do the visualization instead
of my website so really I could do my little scenario where I have
my of the library running on the device sending up to event hubs
through stream analytics to our by...really have to write practically any code
at all to actually see the scenario an action from end-to-end.
So, the summary then I guess is...sort of these five.
Patterns...patterns that I talked about along the way, you know,
that you really audit you really need to think big about the architecture
components use but start with small prototypes
...proof of concept and you just far more likely to have...do it that way telemetry
first...really big believer in that partially as I said before because you
just don't know what you have to you see what you have
then you can make better decisions about it the don't stick your head in the in
...fire hose good advice and life and the dietary.
Then the security thing really has to be a focus from the very
beginning you just cannot put that off until the end and finally building to the reference
architecture to make it easier to move to the sweet as...components become available
this is the only slide that somehow or other got here that I did not right.
I had a couple other things on here but,
so, there's a talk...two and here with clemens' can talk about security ...to share are doing
...ninety overview which probably gone this slide but...too smart to take the
slot right after the keynote and, that's at five in one-a then
there are two of these on-demand sessions one by dan on event tabs one by
...on the...sweets and specifically the ip hub within the
...are definitely good watches and then the other thing that I
head-on here there's a talk by the stream analytics team.
An overview of stream analytics and nl and
other analysis services that I think is really good and then finally the thing that really
I'm really sorry isn't not in here there's a case study by a about I
trans experiences and trying to do security based
programming security based product development and if you search for I
...on microsoft site you'll find it a...ascent is how they
tried to do sort of a trustworthy computing basis that microsoft uses security
focused development and how they try to transform that
...business and their experiences doing that and that's really a good read?
That's it and I've got maybe
four minutes so for a couple of questions if anybody has any otherwise
...hangout for a little bit afterwards and be happy to chat thank you very much.